<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>loicnassif</title>
    <link>http://www.roikku.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on loicnassif</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.roikku.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Friction with Visual Appearance</title>
      <link>http://www.roikku.me/publications/andrews2021-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.roikku.me/publications/andrews2021-et-al/</guid>
      <description>S Andrews, L Nassif, K Erleben, PG Kry
AbstractWe present a novel meso-scale model for computing anisotropic and asymmetric friction for contacts in rigid body simulations that is based on surface facet orientations. The main idea behind our approach is to compute a direction dependent friction coefficient that is determined by an object’s roughness. Specifically, where the friction is dependent on asperity interlocking, but at a scale where surface roughness is also a visual characteristic of the surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.roikku.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.roikku.me/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a computer science master student at McGill University studying under the supervision of Paul G. Kry and Sheldon Andrews. Before that, I completed my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in applied mathematics from the University of Toronto.
My research interests lie in the application of physics theory within computer animation. Currently I focus on modeling friction for rigid body systems. Friction is a complex phenomenon, and we try to develop models that allow for real-time interactions while still preserving physical accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct Imaging of Irregular Satellite Disks in Scattered Light</title>
      <link>http://www.roikku.me/publications/nassif2020-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.roikku.me/publications/nassif2020-et-al/</guid>
      <description>L Nassif-Lachapelle, D Tamayo
AbstractDirect imaging surveys have found that long-period super-Jupiters are rare. By contrast, recent modeling of the widespread gaps in protoplanetary disks revealed by ALMA suggests an abundant population of smaller Neptune to Jupiter-mass planets at large separations. The thermal emission from such lower-mass planets is negligible at optical and near-infrared wavelengths, leaving only their weak signals in reflected light. Planets do not scatter enough light at these large orbital distances, but there is a natural way to enhance their reflecting area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.roikku.me/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.roikku.me/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can email me at loic.nassif-lachapelle@mcgill.ca</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.roikku.me/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.roikku.me/posts/</guid>
      <description>Nothing to see here for now&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
